Tim Mclennan

Frontend Software Engineer

Portfolio: tim-mclennan.github.io/My-Portfolio **Linkedin**: tim-mclennan.github.io/My-Portfolio **Linkedin**: tim-mclennan-0563341aa

Github: github.com/Tim-Mclennan

: 0422286800

SKILLS

Highly proficient in frontend languages and frameworks including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript and React. Familiarity with UX, testing, debugging, responsive design and using Git for version control in an Agile environment. With 4 years of commercial experience, I have excellent problem solving, organisational and interpersonal skills.

EXPERIENCE

NSW Department of Customer Service - Frontend Software Engineer

Mar 2022 - Present

- Developed and maintained web applications using CSS, Javascript, Typescript, React and Redux.
- Debugged, tested and troubleshooted frontend issues, ensuring optimal performance and user experience.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to develop frontend code for multiple on-time projects.

Commonwealth Bank - Frontend Developer

Sep 2020 - Sep 2021

- Developed user interfaces of CBA's web and mobile applications to ensure a positive and efficient user experience.
- Collaborating with UX/UI designers, backend developers, and other team members to implement features and troubleshoot issues.
- Writing clean and maintainable code, following best practices and coding standards for a high-scale web environment.

Mercury Digital - Frontend Developer/Entrepreneur

Jan 2020 - Sep 2020

- Launched a website development agency serving small businesses, leading to crucial growth in customer base and revenue.
- Developed bespoke website solutions leveraging HTML, CSS, WordPress and JavaScript to create user-centric websites.
- Lead a small remote team to create social media marketing campaigns.

Open Colleges - Student Support Team Leader

Apr 2019 - Jun 2020

- Managed a high volume inbound call centre (250+ calls a day)
- Supervised & coached a team of 10-15 student support officers
- First point of contact for customers country-wide (Inbound & Outbound phone support)
- Conducting 1 on 1 performance evaluations/monthly KPI reports

EDUCATION

University of Technology, Sydney - Bachelor of IT

2015 - 2018

A thorough education in all aspects of computing and information systems.

_Nology - Software Engineering Bootcamp

Sep 2021 - March 2022

Full-time, intensive bootcamp focused on full stack software engineering.